ADOLF SCHMUCK

Email: adolf.schmuck@gmail.com | Phone: 619-750-9469 | San Diego, CA 91977

GitHub: https://github.com/answebdev | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adolf-schmuck/

Portfolio: https://adolfschmuck.com/

Web developer with over 10 years of experience in ESL instruction currently focusing on building clean, savvy applications. Seeking to use proven skills in front-end and back-end coding and collaboration developed and improved upon in Web Development Bootcamp to meet the needs of projects involving full-stack technology. An experienced professional with a superb work ethic passionate about developing great products as a front-end web developer.

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, the command line, GitHub, Node.js, NPM, Express.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, Postman, and Heroku.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Lucky Student (Role: Full-stack Developer)

- A full-stack MERN application that allows teachers to select a student at random with the click of a button from their class roster. Users create an account to add and save students to their class roster, as well as add and delete names.
- Languages and technology used: React.js, ES6, MongoDB Atlas, Express.js, Node,js, JavaScript, NPM packages, Animate.css, and CSS.
- Deployed application: https://aqueous-oasis-34129.herokuapp.com

ESL Toolbox (Role: Front-end Developer)

- A resource hub created for students and teachers of ESL. Shared across the instructor community on the Canvas Learning Platform in the ESL department at Grossmont College.
- Languages and technology used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, JavaScript, GraphComment, and ShareThis.
- Live website: https://esl-toolbox.com/

Raygun Circus (Role: Front-end Developer)

- The official website for Raygun Circus, an indie band from San Diego, that features pages with music for users to listen to, embedded YouTube videos, links to related social pages, and more.
- Languages and technology used: JavaScript, Enformed.io, Lightbox, Animate.css, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML.
- Live website: https://rayguncircus.com/

The Simpsons Clicky Game (Role: React Developer)

- A React application that tests the user's memory with a Simpsons-themed memory game.
- Languages and technology used: React.js, ES6, NPM packages: ReactHowler and SweetAlert, Bootstrap, and CSS.
- Deployed application: https://answebdev.github.io/clicky-game/

Bar Finder (Role: Front-end Developer on a team of four)

- A web application that allows the user to search for a bar based on location and bar type, as well as search for drink recipes.
- Languages and technology used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery; Bootstrap, Semantic UI; Firebase; AJAX; APIs from Open Brewery DB, TheCocktailDB, and Google Maps.
- Deployed application: https://brysonelson.github.io/project-gpgp/

Adolf Schmuck Page 2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

San Diego, CA

Freelance Front-end Web Developer, February 2019 – Present

- Designing and developing user-friendly designs utilizing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, and other technology.
- Modifying, updating, and maintaining web applications as needed.
- Diagnosing, troubleshooting, and resolving problems and bugs in code in a timely manner.

Grossmont College, El Cajon, CA

Professor Adjunct, January 2016 - Present

- Organizing and delivering well-developed lesson plans with attention to detail and creativity.
- Fostering a culture of learning and structure to help students succeed in an academic setting.
- Collaborating with co-instructors to fully assist students registered in corequisite courses.

Mesa College (UCSD), San Diego, CA

Professor Adjunct, August 2015 – December 2015

- Provided well-organized lesson plans to help university students succeed in writing program.
- Assessed students' strengths and weaknesses regularly to provide appropriate methods for addressing student needs.
- Successfully led and conducted writing workshops for students to practice revision and editing.

EC San Diego, La Jolla, CA

ESL Instructor, February 2012 - Present

- Delivering instruction in ESL encompassing a wide range of language skills and skill levels.
- Creating and presenting engaging lesson plans that keep students focused and motivated.
- Effectively maintaining classroom structure and student engagement.

Pagoda Academy, Seoul, South Korea

EFL Instructor, January 2011 – December 2011

- Taught conversation and academic classes to adults of a wide range of skill levels.
- Regularly evaluated students emphasizing skills transferable to other classes and contexts.
- Conducted level placement interviews for prospective students.

EDUCATION

UC San Diego Extension, La Jolla, CA

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp Certificate, August 2018 - February 2019

An intensive six-month long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, and React.js.

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Master of Arts in Linguistics

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Basic Certificate in Applied Linguistics and English as a Second Language

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Bachelor of Arts in General Humanities. Minor in German

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with Distinction in Humanities.
- Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society Member.